energyguide.com 2002-06-05

# Privacy Policies: ENERGYguide.com - Lower Your Energy Bills

### ENERGYguide.com Privacy Statement

ENERGYguide.com is a licensee of the [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/) Privacy Program. This statement discloses the privacy practices for ENERGYguide.com. When you visit a Web site displaying the [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/) trust mark, you can expect to be notified of: 

  * What personally identifiable information is collected 
  * Which organization is collecting the information 
  * How the information is used 
  * With whom the information may be shared 
  * What choices are available regarding collection, use and distribution of the information 
  * Which security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under the company's control 
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact [privacy@energyguide.com](mailto:privacy@energyguide.com) or by calling 781/694-3300 or via US Mail at 16 Laurel Avenue, Suite 100, Wellesley, MA 02481. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact  [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/watchdog.html). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns. 

#### Our Commitment to Privacy

ENERGYguide.com has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy of our customers and the information that they provide us. ENERGYguide.com collects and processes information for specified legitimate purposes either directly on the ENERGYguide.com site or through a co-branded partner site (see Co-Branded Partner below). Neither we, nor our co-branded partners, will give away, trade, sell or release any information obtained from our customers. The following headings address how ENERGYguide.com and our co-branded partners gather and use information. 

#### IP Addresses and Cookies

ENERGYguide.com collects the user's IP address and any referring URL. The user's IP address is often not an address that can be traced to their machine, as most users do not employ static IP addresses. Rather, they connect through an ISP, a service that uses DHCP or a proxy server. In these cases, their IP address is not permanently bound to their machine. We use the IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer ENERGYguide.com. IP addresses are also used in aggregate form for traffic analysis. 

When a person visits the site, a cookie is created on the user's machine that stores that visitor's ENERGYguide.com user ID. The cookie is non-sessional and persists on the user's machine for one year at which point it expires. A second cookie is also created to hold session information. It expires as soon as the session terminates (after twenty minutes). ENERGYguide.com also utilizes cookies to track items placed in your shopping cart, deliver content specific to your interests and save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site (See also the Advertising section regarding 3rd party use of cookies on our site) . 

#### Registration Information

ENERGYguide.com's registration form requires users to provide contact information including at a minimum, name, ZIP code and email address. We use customer contact information from the registration form to send users information about our company. Users may opt-out of receiving such information. (see the choice/opt-out section below). 

ENERGYguide.com also asks for email address and ZIP code in order to contact the member and provide them with updates on savings and energy information. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings (see the choice/opt-out section below). 

#### Order Information

ENERGYguide.com uses an order form for customers to request and purchase information, products and services. We collect visitor's contact information (like their email address) and financial information (like their account or credit card numbers). Contact information from the order form is used to send orders to our customers. The customer's contact information is also used to contact members with special offers, site information, surveys to track their site experience and notifications of any site performance issues. Users may opt-out of receiving these mailings (see the choice/opt-out section below). Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services they purchase. 

In some cases we allow the user to signup directly on the Merchant or Content Partner. In this case we may ask for the user's contact information (like name, ZIP code and email address) and pass this over to the Partner. However, this information is only used for the primary purpose for which it was collected. 

In other cases ENERGYguide.com collects all signup info and retains it. In these cases information is either transmitted on a real-time basis or batched and sent to the Merchant or Content Partner on a daily basis. 

In all instances of Order Information, ENERGYguide.com employs multiple security methods to protect the information 

#### Analysis Information

ENERGYguide.com stores personally identifiable information including data provided by visitor from the various tools, calculators and other analytical content on the site. This personal information is collected for internal use only so that we may personalize the site for our members and to communicate directly to them. This information is used anonymously at an aggregate level to analyze user data and understand appropriate products and services for our users. Users will receive energy-savings information and other related mailings unless they have no interest in receiving such notifications and opt out (see the choice/opt-out section below). 

#### Contest Information

From time to time, ENERGYguide.com may promote contests in which we ask visitors for contact information (like their email address). Contact data from our contests are used to send users information about our company. We also utilize contact data, such as email address, to notify the contest winners. Users may opt-out of receiving future notifications on our contests (see the choice/opt-out section below).   

#### Links

ENERGYguide.com contains links to other sites and is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. We encourage users to read the privacy statements for any pages located on other sites. 

#### Advertising

ENERGYguide.com serves its own ads and employs an outside advertising company to display them on our site. These ads may contain cookies. Outside ad companies do not provide us access to this information.   

#### Merchant Partners

ENERGYguide.com partners with energy suppliers, re-billers and product vendors to provide our customers with products, services, online sign-up and "request more information" options. We collect some or all of your personal information like email, name, address, etc., and securely transfer it to our Merchant Partners for use in completing your requested transaction. However, this information is only used for the primary purpose for which it was collected. 

#### Content Partners

ENERGYguide.com partners with other sites to provide content on our site and to make product and service offers to our visitors through "Powered By" relationships. You can identify that you are using a partner's content, etc…when you see a "Powered By" logo for such partners within the ENERGYguide.com site. 

#### Co-Branded Partners

ENERGYguide.com partners with other sites (i.e. utility, real estate and financial sites) to provide energy-related content to their visitors in a co-branded relationship. You can identify that you are using a co-branded partner site by seeing a "Powered by ENERGYguide.com" logo present within another party's site. Your information is only used for the primary purpose for which it was collected.   

#### Choice/Opt-Out

ENERGYguide.com offers users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from both our partners and us when we request information from them. Please see below. ENERGYguide.com offers users the following options for removing their information from our database in order to stop receiving communications from ENERGYguide.com or to terminate our service: 

  * Upon registering, entering a contest, or purchasing a product from ENERGYguide.com, you are given the choice of participating in periodic mailings, and may choose to opt-out; 
  * You can send email to [webmaster@energyguide.com](mailto:webmaster@energyguide.com);
  * After receiving an email, a recipient may choose to opt-out of future mailings.

ENERGYguide.com reserves the right that due to rare unanticipated events it may become necessary to contact you for strictly administrative purposes. 

#### Security

The ENERGYguide.com site has implemented a comprehensive set of security measures to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control. Our servers reside at a secure location provided by WorldCom. These servers employ an all-inclusive implementation of Windows NT security measures that prevent unauthorized system access. All customer information is conducted via encrypted data transfer methods. Credit card transactions are processed by EFI, a leading distributor of energy-efficient products who maintain the strictest security in processing transactions and protecting customer information. These measures are reviewed on a regular basis. All ENERGYguide.com employees are aware of these security procedures via internal education and are periodically briefed on any new security considerations.   

#### Notification of Changes

ENERGYguide.com reserves the right to change, modify or augment any or all parts of this privacy policy. Any changes will be posted immediately on this privacy page so that our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and, under specified situations, how we disclose it. Any changes that may influence the use or storage of user information will first be proposed to all users via e-mail at which point each user will decide whether or not we continue to store and/or use their information. ENERGYguide.com will only use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

#### Correcting/Updating Information

Correcting/Updating Information  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of ENERGYguide.com or your dealings with the Web site or if you need to correct, access or update pertinent Personally Identifiable Information obtained through the site, you can use any of the following contacts: 

Nexus ENERGYguide  
16 Laurel Ave. Suite 100  
Wellesley, MA 02481  
781-694-3300  

#### Legal Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.
